平安夜快樂 艾麗克斯
Merry Christmas Eve, Alex.
他還活著啊
So, he's still alive --
你一定還沒跟媽媽說你懷孕的事吧
must mean you haven't told Mom you're pregnant yet.
我們想謹慎處理好這件事
We want to be careful to do it right.
現在你倒知道謹慎了
Now you're being careful?
我沒辦法再保守秘密了
I can't keep this secret anymore.
看看我
Look at me!
她頭發都發白了
Ugh. She's going gray.
我的天 還真是
Oh my God, she is!
我剛才是在驚訝她的丑發型呢
I was just gasping at the haircut.
我現在似乎一有壓力就會這樣
Apparently, this is what happens when I feel stress now.
好吧 我們一定會在今天告訴他們 好嗎
Well, we're telling them today, okay?
這樣的話 就算媽媽生氣
That way, if Mom freaks,
她也有十天的時間在百慕大冷靜下來
she'll have 10 days in Bermuda to calm down.
行啊 那現在就去啊
Okay, then go now!
她不會有比平安夜心情更好的時候了
She's never in a better mood than on Christmas Eve.
等一下 這樣告訴她怎么樣
Wait, is this a good way to tell her?
我們掛只襪子給"克萊爾外婆"
We hang a stocking for "Grandma Claire,"
然后當她說"我不是外婆"的時候
and when she goes, "I'm not a grandma,"
我們就說 跟海莉和我"滴"寶寶說去吧
we go, "Tell that to Haley and my's baby."
答應我 送孩子去上學 別留家教育
Promise me you won't home school this kid.
媽媽 你在干嘛呢
Hey, Mom. What are you doing?
圣誕賀卡就是一堆廢紙
Ugh, Christmas cards are just clutter.
等下等下等下
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
你可不能扔掉小卡舅舅的賀卡
You can't throw away Uncle Cam's card.
你知道他對鋼琴上的布局有多敏感
You know how sensitive he gets about his piano placement.
還記得那年他的賀卡
Remember that one year where his card
比我們家老保姆的卡片放得靠后了一點嗎
was slightly behind the one from our old babysitter?
我想他用了句迷人的措辭
Mm, I believe he spoke the charming phrase,
"這臭婊子是誰"
"And who is this whore?"
今年圣誕節在外公家過
Well, Christmas is at Grandpa's this year,
所以小卡不會看到它的
so Cam will never see it.
看看這些滑雪橇的北極熊包裝紙
Check out the sledding polar bear paper.
看到它不由自主就會有好心情 對吧
Can't look at that and not be in a good mood, huh?
可不是嗎
Yeah.
我討厭這玩意兒
I am so sick of that stuff.
我為了學校活動跟某孩子訂了5卷
I ordered five rolls from some kid for a school drive.
結果他帶來了50卷... 他的錯
He shows up with fifty -- his fault.
這孩子就哭了起來
Kid bursts into tears.
好像他不會數數是我的錯
Like it's on me that he can't count?
-我那時才六歲 媽媽 -行吧
-I was six, Mom. -Mm.
去百慕大就該這樣穿
Bermuda just gets it --
正式卻不失休閑
formal yet casual.
而且還能看到世界上曬黑最完美的
And home of the most perfectly tanned
大腿下部和膝蓋上部區域
lower thigh, upper knee region in the world.
以后在更衣室要找到百慕大同鄉就很容易了
Not hard to pick out a Bermudan in a locker room.
別了吧 等一下
No. Oh, hang on.
等等 這不對啊
Wait. Well, this can't be right.
這個行程表上說我們有四個航班
This itinerary says we're on four flights
和三次中轉
with three layovers.
是啊
Oh, yeah, um...
記得我在網上找到那個很棒的機票嗎
remember how I found that amazing airline deal online?
記得 可是其中兩個中轉長達六個小時
Yeah, but two of these layovers are six hours each.
是啊 但第三個只有十二分鐘呢
Yes, but the third one's only 12 minutes.
但那是在奧黑爾機場
But it's at O'Hare.
親愛的 我們得在十二分鐘內
Honey, we'll have to sprint
從機場的這頭跑到那頭
from one end of the airport to the other.
當我們12月27日在百慕大醒來的時候
It'll all be worth it when we wake up on December 27th
一切都是值得的 那里天氣預報顯示...
in Bermuda, where the forecast predicts...
熱霧
hot fog.
我們就不能坐直達班機嗎
Can't we just take a direct flight?
不能變更 條款寫得很清楚
There's no changes, the terms were very clear.
這是一個新網站促銷活動
It was part of a promotion for a new website
那網站叫做機.票網
called Tickets.Plane
對了 我要在附近帶人看房
Oh, yeah, I have a showing right down the street.
好的 等一下
Okay. Wait, hang on.
先別急著走
Don't leave. Don't leave.
低等經濟艙是什么
What is Economy Minus?
其實應該是升等才對
A plus, actually,
因為這艙里沒有人會嫉妒坐不到走道位
since no one's jealous of people with aisle seats,
這基本上是兩排創新的十八人長椅
because it's basically two innovative 18-person benches
面對面放著
facing each other.
菲爾
Phil?!
-什么事 -沒事
- What? - Nothing.
誰動了小卡的賀卡
Who moved Cam's card?
如果不放在壁爐上小卡會很不開心的
He's gonna be very upset if he's not on the mantel!
我把它放在抽屜里了 等他來再拿出來
I put it in a drawer until he gets here.
上面的閃粉粘得到處都是
That glitter was getting on everything.
我還吸進了一點
I breathed some of that in.
我現在咳出的都是金粉
I cough gold now.
歌洛莉亞 你有一個哥倫比亞來的包裹
Gloria, you got a package from Colombia.
看來你們政府拿回飛機跑道了
Must mean the government took back the airstrip.
那是我親戚們送的禮物
Those are the gifts from my cousins!
真好看
Beautiful!
在老家我們叫它"毛衣之圣誕[西語]"
Back home we call these sueteres de Navidad.
所以就是圣誕毛衣唄
So...Christmas sweaters.
快穿上 我們來拍張照
Put them on so we can take a picture.
這毛衣真柔軟
Wow, these are really soft.
可舒適保暖了
Damn cozy is what they are.
看 他們還送了香蕉葉花環
Oh, look, they also sent a banana leaf wreath.
香蕉蜘蛛
Banana spider!
-什么 -那是什么鬼玩意
- What?! - What is that?!
是一種致命毒蜘蛛 能殺死人的
It's a deadly spider! It will kill you!
我知道致命是什么意思
I know what deadly means!
它去哪了
Well, where'd it go?
我的家居鞋不包腳后跟
I'm wearing backless house slippers!
我覺得它跑到
I think it ran over to the --
它占領圣誕樹了
He took the tree!
只有我覺得有點癢嗎
Am I the only one who feels kinda itchy?
毛衣有問題
The sweaters.
明處有一只 暗處上百千
Where there's one, there's many!
-快跑 -我們走
- Run! - Let's go!
老天 它占領到遙控器了
Dear God, he's got the remote.
來笑一個
Okay, smile!
這個完了我們能去看看手機嗎
Can we go look at phones after this?
不行 莉莉 圣誕節不能給你手機當禮物
No, Lily, you are not getting a cell phone for Christmas.
手機很貴 你還沒有證明自己
They're expensive, and you haven't proven yourself
有足夠的責任感擁有自己的一部手機
responsible enough to own one yet.
我夠有責任感了 我都到一個陌生的國家
Uh, I was responsible enough to come to a foreign country
和兩個陌生人過日子了
and build a life with two strangers.
你想晚點睡覺的時候用過這理由了
Okay, you used that one to get a later bedtime, all right?
卡爾 你是下一個
Oh, Cal, you're next.
我們想給卡爾一個完美圣誕
We want Cal to have a perfect Christmas.
這挺有難度 畢竟他媽媽在監獄
It's tough with his mom being in prison.
另外 他的圣誕季開始得有點糟糕
Plus, his holiday season kind of got off to a rough start.
你知道嗎 我們選的所有裝飾品里
You know, of all of our wonderful ornament selects,
這倆是我的最愛
these are my fave.
圣誕快樂[M.C]
Merry Christmas!
也是米奇和小卡的首字母縮寫
From Mitch and Cam!
? 馴鹿屋頂上停下來 ?
♪ Up on the rooftop, reindeer pause ♪
? 圣誕老人蹦下雪橇 ?
♪ Out jumps good old Santa Claus ♪
? 背著玩具爬下煙囪 ?
♪ Down through the chimney with lots of toys ♪
? 帶給孩子們圣誕歡樂 ?
♪ All for the little ones' Christmas joy ♪
? 呵呵呵 誰不想來呢 ?
♪ Ho, ho, ho, who wouldn't go? ♪
? 圣誕老人屋頂上 嗒嗒嗒 ?
♪ Up on the housetop, click, click, click ♪
-他沒事 真的沒事 -挺好的
- He was fine. Fine! - He was fine.
我們還沒唱完三節和一段合唱
We barely got through three verses
就反應過來自己的過失了
and a repeat chorus before we realized our mistake.
-這么"短"時間還下了場暴風雨 -是啊
- Although that rainstorm came out of nowhere. - Yeah.
圣誕快樂 小卡爾
Merry Christmas, little Cal!
莉莉 帶你表弟過去玩一會兒
Lily, take your cousin over there. Relax a little.
去吧
Okay, go.
-你好 -你好
- Hi! - Hi!
圣誕老人 不知道你能不能幫我們一個小忙
Hey, Santa. So, just wondering if you could you do us a favor
告訴我們小侄子想要什么圣誕禮物
and tell us what our nephew just asked for for Christmas?
我認識你 你是那個律師
I know you. You're that lawyer.
完了 這么一開頭就沒好事
Oh, no. This is never good.
你是那個指控我公共場合酗酒的助理地檢
You're the ADA who charged me with public intoxication.
給我判了五十個小時社區服務
Got me sentenced to fifty hours community service --
包括為商場扮圣誕老人
working as a mall Santa is part of it.
真的抱歉 我們能大人不記小人過嗎
Okay. Well, I'm sorry. But can't we move past that?
我們真的需要知道小侄子想要什么
We really need to know what our nephew asked for.
他想要更寬松的司法體系
He asked for a more lenient justice system.
我不太相信 他立場挺保守派
Well, I doubt that. He's pretty conservative.
我們不能承認關系 只能假裝室友
We have to pretend to be roommates.
我們能趕緊的嗎
Can we move this along?
這周我只能和孩子待四個小時
I only have my kids for four hours this week.
圣誕快樂 司法萬歲
Merry Christmas.
你知道 作為一個前任商場圣誕老人
You know what? As a former mall Santa,
我發過誓不評判一個在崗的圣誕老人
I vowed never to comment on a sitting Santa,
但是你真讓這紅白制服丟臉
but you're a disgrace to the red and white.
菲爾 我剛和我爸通完電話
Phil, I just got off the phone with my dad.
平安夜要挪到我們家過了
We're moving Christmas Eve to our house.
我得趕緊出去買點雜貨
I got to run out and get some groceries.
一會見 拜
See you soon. Bye.
圣誕樹呢
Where's the tree?
禮物都到哪去了
Where are the gifts?
我想你取消過圣誕節 因為你發現我...
I assumed you canceled Christmas because you found out that I --
不過我打斷你說話了
But I interrupted you.
你爸是不是把東西拿去賣房那里了
Did your dad take them to his showing?
他總干這種事 把我的裝飾偷拿走
He's always doing this -- he steals my decorations
去布置他賣的房子 增加家庭氣息
to stage his houses to make them homier.
他保證過不會再犯的
He swore he would stop doing this!
至少他沒拿走"發環"
At least he left the "Wreaf."
是花環
Wreath.
兩種發音我都有聽人說過啦
Eh, I've heard it both ways.
我也聽過 但不代表是對的
No, I have, too. Doesn't make it right.
我們該如何是好
What are we supposed to do?
沒有圣誕樹 就沒法辦圣誕節晚宴了
We can't host a Christmas without a tree.
經過去年的事件后 他們不是不準你
I thought you weren't allowed to host Christmas anymore
再辦圣誕節晚宴了嗎
after last year.
我突發妙想 用創新方法烹飪了火雞
I took a swing at a new way to prepare turkey.
火雞都沒解凍
Well, this is frozen.
不是的 爸爸 你只是切到了骨頭
No, Dad, you just -- you hit a bone.
我從《頂級大廚》學到的
I saw this on "Top Chef."
他們只用一小時就煮好了一整只火雞
They cooked an entire turkey in one hour.
盧克已經吃了 你還好好的 對吧
Luke had some, you're fine. Aren't you, buddy?
看喬有沒有事
Check on Joe.
你爸不接電話
Oh, your father isn't answering.
這事你一定知情 對吧
You knew about this, didn't you?
我能看出來你心里藏了秘密
I could tell you were hiding something.
菲爾
Phil?
Phil!
菲...
Ph-- Oh!
這間家庭影院完全隔音
This theater is totally soundproof,
所以不會有人聽到你大聲吼吉姆
so no one will hear you yelling at Jim
叫他把襪子撿起來 桑迪
to pick up his socks, Sandy.
她有時的確"很大聲"
She does get loud.
這房子優點多多
So, all of this,
而且還在很好的學區里
plus it's in a great school dist...rict.
老天 這房子剛被搶劫了嗎
Oh my God, was this house just robbed?
我就跟你說這一區很亂吧
I told you this was a sketchy area.
我不要再經歷一次入室搶劫
I am not going through another home invasion
而我和孩子們在安全屋外狂錘門你都不開
with the kids and me banging on the panic room door.
你們慢慢聊 我看看
So, you guys chat, and I'll, uh, take a minute,
能不能找到替代的圣誕樹
see if I can find a replacement tree
以及九份包裝紙一模一樣的禮物
and nine identically wrapped gifts.
這辦法一定能讓你媽心情變好
It's the perfect way to get your mom in a good mood.
你想想啊 杯子蛋糕就是小蛋糕
Think about it -- cupcakes are little cakes
就像嬰兒就是小人兒
just like babies are little people.
應該吧
I guess.
我只是希望一切能順利進行
I just want this to go well.
懷了這個孩子 我很開心
I'm in a really good place with this baby,
我希望媽媽也為此開心
and I want my mom to be, too.
她今早心情不是很好
She wasn't in the best mood this morning.
今天是平安夜
It's Christmas Eve.
她不可能一整天都像變相怪杰一樣臉色發青
She can't stay a Grinch all day.
謝謝 我跟除蟲人員聯系過了
Thank you. That was the exterminator.
他馬上趕過來
He is, uh, on his way,
但除蟲那幾天 他得用帳篷把房子圍起來
but he's gonna have to tent the house for a couple of days.
我打算給我們訂酒店
And I'm trying to book us a hotel,
但電話總斷線
but the call keeps dropping.
喬 我們到后院去 那里信號比較好
Joe, let's go to the backyard. There's better reception.
聽著 我有東西落屋里了
Hey, listen. I left something inside.
你得去幫我拿出來 這應該能保你平安
I need you to get it for me. This should keep you safe.
你瘋了嗎 我才不要回去那個蜘蛛巢穴
Are you crazy? I'm not going back into that spider's nest.
好吧 我也討厭蜘蛛
Fine, I hate them, too.
問題是 我身上的雄性麝香會吸引它們
The problem is, they're attracted to my musk.
前不久我到動物園里的昆蟲間
I went to the insect room at the zoo a while back,
它們馬上像犯人一樣開始狂拍玻璃
and they all started banging on the glass like inmates.
你落什么在屋里了 這么重要
What'd you leave in there that's so important?
是藥
It's a medication.
我沒事 但我沒告訴你媽
I'm fine, but I didn't tell your mom
因為我不想她擔心
'cause I didn't want her to worry.
我們不能順路到酒水商店
Can we just stop by a liquor store
幫你加滿"處方藥"嗎
and refill your "Prescription."
都說了是藥 聽著
It's a medicine! Look...
我們住的酒店一定有頂級水療
I'm sure our hotel has a top notch spa.
也許還能加個熱石按摩
One that might add a, uh, hot stone massage,
和花草浸浴
an herbal soak...
我像是會被物質收買的人嗎
Do I look like someone who can be bought?
不像 但你看起來應該會喜歡
No, but you do look like someone who might enjoy
四手巴厘島式海藻按摩
a four-handed Balinese seaweed swaddle.
你個奸詐的老混蛋
You son of a bitch.
卡爾 你跟圣誕老人聊什么啦
So, Cal, what did you and Santa talk about?
那是秘密
It's a secret.
我 現金就行
Me, I'd be fine with just cash.
你們要煩心的事夠多了 給你們減輕負擔
You guys have enough on your plate.
你也別想自己去買個電話 好吧
Okay, you're not buying yourself a phone, all right?
圣誕老人休息了
Ooh, Santa's on break.
莉莉 去和卡爾坐在一起
Okay, Lily, go sit with Cal again.
你們要我幫忙 好歹加個請字吧
You guys need me -- maybe throw a please in there.
-好的 嗨 -嗨
- Yeah. Hi! - Hi!
真的是一年中最美好的時刻
Oh, it really is the most wonderful time of the year.
-真美好 -不是嗎 你介不介意
- Beautiful. - Isn't it? So, listen, do you mind if --
你們覺得你們是第一個
Do you think you're the first parents
想偷看我名冊的家長嗎
wanting to take a peek at my scroll?
最好在我的靴子[屁股]里塞點東西
Better stick something in my bootie.
-哇 哇 -什么鬼
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. - I'm sorry. What?
塞錢在我鞋子里 變態
Cash in the slipper, perv.
-你 -嗯 我有
- Oh. Do you wanna... - Yeah, yeah, I got -- I got,
我有十塊
uh -- I've got $10.
謝謝
Thank you.
不 這只是玩具列表
No, this is just a list of toys.
孩子的名字沒在上面
None of the kids' names are next to them.
你知道嗎
Oh, oh. You know what?
我們看下卡爾排隊的照片
Uh, we'll look at pictures of Cal in line
把他之后的孩子
and then match the kids up behind him
和單子上的玩具連在一起
with the toys on the list.
好 我猜這個亞洲小孩
Okay, so, well, I guess this Asian kid,
他可能想要個...
he maybe wants the, uh --
沒時間在這里回避種族刻板印象了
There's no time to be politically correct.
-他想要個計算器 -計算器
- He wants the calculator. - Calculator.
他特別想要
And he wants it bad. Yeah.
等下 那意味著
Wait, does that mean that
這個小男孩想要芭比造型頭嗎
this little boy wants the Barbie Styling Head?
沒錯 看那精心打扮的腳
Yep, look at the turned-out foot.
他當然是想要芭比造型頭
Oh, of course he wants the Barbie Styling Head.
這就意味著卡爾想要
Which means Cal wants...
風火輪小汽車
Hot Wheels!
好的
Okay, okay.
-我們走 謝謝 -謝謝
- Let's go. Thank you! - Thank you.
別擔心 他們會回來的
Don't worry. They come back.
求你告訴我你們已經去說了
Please tell me you told Mom and Dad.
沒 但我們會用歌聲告訴你們爸媽
No, but we're gonna tell them in song.
聽聽這部分
Listen to this part.
? 很快像我們一樣可愛的寶寶 ?
♪ Soon a baby as cute as us ♪
? 會從海莉的子宮里出來 ?
♪ Will spring forth from Haley's uterus ♪
我好喜歡
I love it!
她在騙人 她就想我們趕快說
She's lying. She just wants us
這樣她的濕疹就會消失
to get it over with so her eczema will go away.
我才沒有 天啊
I don't have -- Oh, my God!
好 你記著
Okay, you got this.
你比那些東西速度更快
You're quicker than those things.
-我很懷疑 -你更聰明
- I doubt that. - You're smarter.
巧婦難為無米之炊
I can't make a web out of nothing.
-你還有武器 -吹葉機嗎
- Plus, you got a weapon. - A leaf blower?
這家伙能把博美犬吹過籬笆
Hey, that thing can blow a Pomeranian through a hedge.
這么說吧 隔壁的小咪咪
Let's just say little Mimi from next door
再不會來我們家草坪了
won't be visiting our lawn anymore.
趁你媽沒回來 快點
Now hurry up before your mom gets back.
我們保持聯系
We'll be in constant communication.
快 快 快
Go. Go, go, go.
保持警惕
Keep your head on a swivel.
去我的浴室 記住
Head for my bathroom. Remember.
那蜘蛛能覺察最微弱的恐懼
That spider can sense the subtlest sign of fear.
有東西爬過了我的腳
Something just ran past my foot.
我去 停電了
Damn it, the power's out!
我也要走了
Then so am I!
別啊 你們現在勢均力敵了
No! You just leveled the playing field.
他們有四雙眼睛
They have eight eyes.
你只有一雙
You only have two.
停電的話它們唯一的優勢也沒啦
You just took away their one advantage.
它們的毒液呢
What about their sac of poison?
好 我到浴室了
Okay, I'm in the bathroom.
很好 很好 藥在
Good, good. The medication...
底下的柜子里
is down below in the cabinet.
你讓我把手伸進
You want me to reach my hand
黑暗又潮濕的產卵區嗎
into a dark, damp breeding ground?
就在右后邊
It's all the way in the back on the far right.
用手摸著找那個罐子
Just feel around for the jar.
所以還要來回移動我的手
So, skitter my hand back and forth?
這基本上就是蜘蛛求偶舞了
That's basically a spider mating dance!
拿到了
Got it.
回答我 完畢
Talk to me, over.
曼尼
Manny!
還不走
Not leaving!
還要買
Still shopping!
被搶劫還不夠慘似的
As if getting robbed wasn't bad enough,
現在讓我們搞圣誕聚餐
now that we were hosting Christmas,
我得在克萊爾回家前 把新的圣誕樹
I had to get a new tree and gifts into the house
和禮物搬進家里來
before Claire got home.
幸好我還有一份她的禮物清單
Fortunately, I had a copy of her gift list.
心里有點毛骨悚然
It was eerie how many of these events
這么多的事情都跟我正在寫的童書情節重疊
were lining up with the plot of my children's book in progress,
我的書名叫《拯救圣誕的房產中介》
"The Realtor Who Saved Christmas."
-你好 -哥們兒 幫個忙
- Hello? - Buddy, I need a favor.
還記得上次因為你數學太爛
Remember that polar bear wrapping paper
害我們買了好多的北極熊包裝紙嗎
you made us buy so much of because you can't do math?
拿上幾卷
Grab a couple rolls of it,
20分鐘后到家門外等我
meet me out in front of the house in 20 minutes.
都用完了 老媽用了最后一卷包今年的禮物
We're all out. Mom used the last of it on this year's gifts.
該死 我需要很多 我要去哪...
Damn it! I need a bunch of it. Where am I supposed to f--
? 哈利路亞 ?
♪ Hallelujah ♪
? 哈利路亞 哈利路亞 ?
♪ Hallelujah, Hallelujah ♪
沒事了 盧克
All good, Luke.
我們買到了我們要的東西
Well, we got what we need.
我很高興有人今年終于得到了他想要的
I'm glad someone's getting what they want this year.
這樣吧 我的手機給你
You know what? Here, take my phone.
如果你一天內沒搞丟 手機就歸你了
If you can get through a day without losing it, it's yours.
你肯定是踩到什么發膠上了
You must've run through some hairspray.
你的靴子現在跟捕蠅紙一樣
Your boots are like flypaper.
所以那款膠才被禁用啊
That's why that spray was banned.
小鳥們飛過發膠工廠
Birds were flying over the factory
然后就會黏到一起
and getting stuck together.
等等 等一下 等一下
Hey, wait, wait a second. Wait a second.
這就是你的藥嗎
This is your medication?
"懷舊派胳膊肘潤滑霜"
"Good Old Fashioned Elbow Grease?"
我的手肘干得厲害
I suffer from dry elbow.
我冒著生命危險就為了這個嗎
That's what I risked my life for?
光滑的手肘是所有叉腰姿勢的必備
Supple elbows are heavily featured in every good power pose.
我就是這樣登上《衣柜世界》的封面
That's how I got the cover to Closet World.
我真的是硬生生靠胳膊肘擠上去的
I literally elbowed my way to the top.
我訂了個酒店
I booked us a hotel.
曼尼 你跟喬同住一間
Manny, you're sharing a room with Joe.
這事你給我搞定
Fix that.
你在暖氣片上烤什么東西呢
What are you roasting on the space heater?
我之前把卡片扔到垃圾桶里
Oh, I threw those cards in the trash.
結果都泡濕了
They got all soggy.
連小卡舅舅的都是嗎
Even Uncle Cam's?
那些卡片你得留七年啊
You have to save those for seven years,
跟納稅申報單一樣
like tax returns.
你好呀 菲爾
Hello, Phil.
沒錯
Oh, that's right.
圣誕樹回歸原位了
The tree's back where it belongs.
是你偷的
You stole it?!
不 是你偷的
Oh, no, you did.
跟你以前偷了我的塑料感恩節火雞家族
Just like you stole my family of plastic Thanksgiving turkeys,
我的充氣復活節兔子
my inflatable Easter bunny,
還有我的山姆大叔彩陶罐一樣
and my Uncle Sam pinata,
都搬到你的房屋開放日去了
all for your open houses.
今天是洗清
Today was my chance
我冤情的機會
to shed a very unfair reputation.
克萊爾
Claire --
我只不過害兩個人進了醫院一次
I put two people in the hospital one time,
大家就把我當圣誕節殺手
and now I'm a Christmas ruiner.
著火了
Fire!
我的天哪 去拿滅火器
Oh, my God! Get the extinguisher!
是小卡的閃粉賀卡 我就知道
Aah! It's Cam's glitter card! I knew it!
后退
Stand back!
樹
The tree!
禮物
The gift
這個 那個
The -- The --
用完了
It's out!
我和盧克做噴氣背包時用的肯定是這滅火器
This must be the one Luke and I used for our jet pack prototype.
是我們太傻了 根本就沒什么完美的時間點
You know, we're being crazy. There is no perfect moment.
我們就像大人一樣上去知會一聲就行了
We're just going to walk in there like adults and tell them.
親愛的
Honey...
沒救了
It's no use.
一切都結束了 菲爾
It's over, Phil.
這房子聞著一股煙味兒
The house smells like smoke,
我們沒有圣誕樹
we have no tree
還有九份燒焦又濕透的禮物
and nine scorched, yet soaking-wet gifts.
最糟的是 米奇爾聽了肯定幸災樂禍
Worst of all, I have to make Mitchell's day
因為我得告訴他把聚會改到他家
by telling him we're moving the party to his house
而我永遠不能再主辦聚會了
and I'm on permanent host probation forever.
誰知道呢
Who knows?
或許幾年后他們會丟給我一個小破節日
Maybe in a couple years they'll toss me a pity holiday --
"歡迎來到我的無酒精地球日早午餐"
"Welcome to my non-alcoholic Earth Day brunch."
好消息是
In brighter news,
幾小時后我就要坐上螺旋槳飛機了
I am getting on a prop plane in a couple hours.
現在還有百慕大三角這回事吧
Bermuda Triangle's still a thing, right?
克萊爾
Claire.
親愛的 我現在應付不來
Honey, I just can't right now.
我沒心情
I'm not in the mood for --
怎么做到的
How?
我送你的圣誕快樂
Merry Christmas from me.
你之前偷偷跑出去
Did you sneak out earlier
買了這些東西掩蓋你的行為嗎
and buy all this stuff to cover your tracks?
或者你可以選擇相信這是圣誕奇跡
Or you can choose to believe it's a Christmas miracle.
我選擇奇跡
I choose miracle.
節日快樂
Happy holidays!
謝謝你們接手
Thank you for taking over.
你拯救了一切 圣誕快樂
You saved the day! Merry Christmas.
你知道的 我就是這么厲害
Well, you know, it's kind of what I do.
快來 飲料在廚房
Come on, drinks in the kitchen.
-太好了 -太好了
- Yay! All right! - All right!
曼尼 你頭上怎么起了個小包
Ooh, Manny, what's up with the noggin bump?
什么 哪
What? Where?
不 看起來像是香蕉蜘蛛咬的
Oh, no. That looks like a banana spider bite!
不是咬的 他撞到了頭
It's not a bite, he bumped his head.
不 看起來像被咬了
No, that looks like a bite.
我姐姐被密蘇里青貯窖蜘蛛咬過
My sister got bit by a Missouri Silo Spider --
失去了一根腳趾
lost a toe.
但結局很好 她天生有十一根腳趾
Happy ending -- she was born with eleven.
曼尼 我們得去醫院檢查
Manny, we need to get that checked.
可以用解毒劑
There is an antidote,
但假如你以前從沒被這種蜘蛛咬過
but if you have never been bitten by the spider,
可能是致命的
it might kill you.
-我們上車去 -杰
- Let's go to the car. - I -- Jay.
停下 他沒被咬
Stop! He wasn't bitten.
他撞到了頭 他之前回到房子里去
He bumped his head when he went back in the house
幫我拿 藥
to grab my...medication.
什么藥
What medication?
我的天 爸 你還好嗎
Oh, my God, Dad, are you okay?
我們會挺過去的 伙計
We're gonna get through this, buddy.
是一種胳膊肘霜 每天晚上
It's an elbow cream that I secretly use
我都在歌洛莉亞睡著后偷偷用
every night after Gloria falls asleep.
你讓咱兒子進入致命毒蛛的巢穴
You sent our son into the nest of a deadly spider
就為了拿潤膚霜
for a beauty cream?
這是藥
It's a medicine
用來治療令人心碎的干胳膊肘癥
that treats the heartbreaking condition of dry elbow!
這是獸醫才能開的處方藥
It requires a veterinarian's prescription
因為原本是給犀牛和大象用的
because it's primarily used on rhinos and elephants.
看來盡管我們正朝完美社會大步前進
I see on our march to become a perfect society,
人們仍舊允許胳膊肘羞辱
elbow shaming is still allowed.
我胳膊肘有時也有點干
I get a little dry sometimes.
你要記住你并不比別人差在哪里
Hey! You're just as much a person as everybody else.
我不敢相信你虛榮到這個地步
I can't believe that you're so vain that you --
等等 你鞋底上粘的
Wait, is that my Christmas card
是我的圣誕賀卡嗎
stuck on the bottom of your shoe?
為什么被燒焦了
And why-why is it singed?
你不能再這么看重賀卡了
Ugh, you got to be less about the cards.
我們都這么想
We all think it.
你不是在衛生間噴光了一罐強力發膠嗎
Didn't you empty a can of powerful hairspray in the bathroom?
你也去衛生間了嗎
And did you go in there, too?
好吧 我得拿點東西 行了吧
Fine! I needed something, okay?
但至少我是自己去拿的
But at least I went in myself.
因為你用二十美元雇我我沒答應
After you offered me $20 and I said no.
我們中有些人是不會被收買的
Some of us can't be bought.
你要拿什么
What did you need?
無論是什么 我們會一起陪你挺過去
Whatever it is, we're gonna get through this.
防磨牙牙套
A night guard.
我不想告訴你 但每天晚上
I didn't want to tell you, but every night,
我都等你睡著后戴上
I wait for you to fall asleep, so I put it on.
太沒有吸引力了
It's so unattractive.
就這樣
That's it?
太不性感了 我看起來好丑
Ith not thex-thee. I look hideouth!
終于從神性中蹦出點人味兒了
Oh, that really humanizes her.
我不喜歡
I don't care for it.
我的一顆牙都松了
Okay, one of my teeth is loose.
我求求你去告訴他們吧
I am begging you to tell them.
這就是我打扮的目的啊
That's what this is.
我打扮成圣誕老人并從煙囪落下
I'm coming down the chimney as Santa,
討喬與卡爾開心
delighting Joe and Cal.
媽能看到他跟孩子多投緣
Mom will see how good he is with kids
就會對我懷孕的事放心許多
and then be super chill with us being pregnant.
我卡住了
I'm stuck.
好啦 大家都進來吧 全家福時間到
Okay, everybody, come on, picture time!
到圣誕樹前集合 來吧
In front of the tree, let's go.
天啊 你別出聲
Oh, God. Just be quiet!
你在這里啊 對了 迪蘭呢
There you are. Okay, where's Dylan?
媽 你真有心
Aww, Mom.
想什么呢 我們需要有人幫忙拍照啊
What? We need somebody to take the picture.
太狠心了
Harsh.
什么聲音
What was that?
我們每年不是都會生火的嗎
Don't we always have the fire on?
-沒有 -我挺確定有
- No! - I'm sure we do.
我們去年用那火把克萊爾沒熟的火雞烤熟
Last year we used it to finish cooking Claire's turkey pieces.
杰 去生火
Jay, go turn it on.
等等 等等 等等
Wait! Wait, wait, wait.
各位... 各位12歲以下小朋友先離開下
Every-- Everybody 12 and under, out.
什么 親愛的 這是怎么了
What? Honey, what's going on?
迪蘭卡在煙囪里了
Dylan's stuck in the chimney.
為什么
Why?
他打扮成圣誕老人
He's dressed up as Santa.
想要從煙囪而降來給孩子發禮物
He was gonna hand presents out to the kids.
別現在告訴他們啊 我想跟你一起公布
Don't tell them now. I want to be with you!
告訴我們什么
Tell us what?
沒什么 可以之后再說
Nothing. It can wait.
不能再等了 求求你
No, it can't! Please!
我的全身器官都要停止運作了
My organs are shutting down!
好吧 行 我...
Okay, fine. I...
我們有個事情要宣布
We have an announcement.
我跟迪蘭要生寶寶了
Dylan and I are having a baby.
他們表情笑了嗎
Are they smiling?
你懷孕了嗎
You're pregnant?
是的
Yes.
我們為此感到十分開心
And w-we're really happy about it.
怎么可能會不開心呢
Why wouldn't you be?
媽 你呢
Mom?
這消息需要點時間消化 但...
It's -- it's a lot to process at once, and...
寶寶呢 太棒了
A baby. Unbelievable!
-恭喜你們 -天啊 小寶寶呢
- Congratulations! - Oh, my gosh! A baby!
天啊
Oh, God.
你處理的方式比我當年強多了
You handled that a lot better than I did back in the day.
表面而已 我的內心跟你一樣
Outside. On the inside, I'm you.
能來人救救我的命嗎
Can somebody save my life?
-小卡 你抓一只腳 -好
- Oh, Cam, grab a foot. - Yep.
天啊 他真的卡得好死啊
God, he's really wedged in there.
如果我們能有某種得過獎的
Ah, if only we had some kind of award-winning,
胎盤基底的潤滑霜就好了
placenta-based lubricant.
行行行
Fine!
給 迪蘭 你抹一點這個
Here, Dylan, use a little bit of this.
真不敢相信要有個小迪蘭從你身體蹦出
I can't believe a little Dylan is gonna pop out of you!
會是什么樣子啊
What would that even look like?
大家都過來拍全家福吧
Everybody come on in for the picture!
我設置個定時拍照
I'll set the timer.
一切都會船到橋頭自然直吧
This is all gonna work out, right?
肯定會啦
Definitely. Yeah.
稍等 我得露出我的美肘
Hang on. Let me get my elbows ready.
大家露出笑容 喊"寶寶"
Okay, everybody smile, say "Baby!"
寶寶
Baby!
? 神圣冬青裝飾著大廳 ?
♪ Deck the halls with boughs of holly, ♪
? 這是個歡樂的季節 ?
♪ Tis the season to be jolly, ♪
? 穿上我們的喜樂[基]衣裳 ?
♪ Don we now our gay apparel, ♪
? 我們是不是把孩子們忘在卡萊爾家 ?
♪ Did we leave the kids at Claire's house? ♪
? 真的該給莉莉買手機了 ?
♪ Lily really needs a cellphone. ♪
? 跟著我踏著快樂的步伐 ?
♪ Follow me in merry measure, ♪